二零二四年成都市中考英语听力：一听句子，根据所听到的内容选择正确
答语。
每小题念两遍。
One, how's your day?
How's your day?
Two, thank you so much for watering my flowers.
Thank you so much for watering my flowers.
Three, let's go to the movies on Saturday.
Let's go to the movies on Saturday.
Four, you play the guitar very well.
You play the guitar very well.
Five, can you come to my party next Wednesday?
Can you come to my party next Wednesday?
二，听句子，选择与所听句子内容相符的图片。
每小题念两遍。
Six, this is a train for a short tour.
This is a train for a short tour.
Seven, you are supposed to be quiet in the library.
You are supposed to be quiet in
have you ever read the story How He Shoots the Suns?
Have you ever read the story How He Shoots the Suns?
Nine, here's the result of the survey on children's reading habits.
Here's the result of the survey on children's reading habits.
Ten, in China some people eat very long noodles for their birthday.
In China some people eat very long noodles for their birthday.
三，听对话，根据对话内容及问题选择正确答案。
每小题念两遍。
Eleven, Tony, what's your favorite sport, basketball or football?
Neither. I like playing volleyball best.
Question, what's the boy's favorite sport?
Tony, what's your favorite sport, basketball or football?
Neither. I like playing volleyball best.
what's the boy's favorite sport?
may I have the bill please?
Sure, four dollars for the chicken sandwich and two dollars for the drink.
Question, how much is the bill?
May I have the bill please?
Sure, four dollars for the chicken sandwich and two dollars for the drink.
Question, how much is the bill?
Thirteen, can you speak Chinese Judy?
No, I can't, but I can speak French and Russian.
don't know Russian, but I can speak a little French.
which language can they both speak?
Can you speak Chinese Judy?
No, I can't, but I can speak French and Russian.
I don't know Russian, but I can speak a little French.
Question, which language can they both speak?
Fourteen, where's Dick?
Doesn't he come to school today?
He's at home, he hurt his foot yesterday.
Luckily, wasn't serious or he'll be in hospital now.
where's Dick now?
Where's Dick? Doesn't he come to school today?
He's at home, he hurt his foot yesterday.
Luckily, it wasn't serious or he'll be in hospital now.
Question, where's Dick now?
Fifteen, hello, front desk.
How can I help?
I want to make coffee, but there's no hot water in my room.
Okay, I'll send someone to bring you some at once.
what does the man want?
Hello, front desk.
How can I help?
I want to make coffee, but there's no hot water in my room.
Okay, I'll send someone to bring you some at once.
Question, what does the man want?
Sixteen. Hey, do know Blue Ocean?
Yeah, the new restaurant.
The food is fresh and delicious.
How about the service?
Pretty good. And the pictures on the wall make you feel relaxed?
what are they mainly talking about?
Hey, do you know Blue Ocean?
Yeah, the new restaurant.
The food is fresh and delicious.
How about the service?
Pretty good. And the pictures on the wall make you feel relaxed?
Question, what are they mainly talking about?
Seventeen. Hey, I love your new exercise bike.
It must be great to have one of Well, dot, dot, dot, yes, I know.
What does that mean?
I like it, but I have much to do every day.
I just don't use it often.
Question, how is the man's life?
Hey, I love your new exercise bike.
It must be great to have one of Well, dot, dot, yes, I know.
What does that mean?
I like it, but I have much to do every day.
I just don't use it often.
Question, how is the man's life?
Eighteen. What's your dream job?
Let me see.
I want to work for a newspaper.
Why? You know, I enjoy meeting different people and want to write stories about
them, especially firemen.
I think I are heroes.
Question, what does the boy want to be?
What's your dream job?
Let me see.
I want to work for a newspaper.
Why? You know, I enjoy meeting different people and want to write stories about
them, especially firemen.
I think they are heroes.
Question, does the boy want to be?
Nineteen. Laura, it's already nine o What are you doing now?
I'm still making a lantern.
Is it so difficult?
It's been half an hour since you started.
No, I just want to make it more beautiful.
I'll finish in ten minutes.
Question, when will the girl finish her lantern?
Laura, it's already nine o What are you doing now?
I'm still making a lantern.
Is it so difficult?
It's been half an hour since you started.
No, I just want to make it more beautiful.
I'll finish in ten minutes.
will the girl finish her lantern?
Twenty. Hello, mom.
It's Bob. I'm so sorry.
What happened? I broke your glass doll yesterday.
I know it means a lot to you.
I'm afraid you may get angry.
So I hid it under my quilt.
It's okay. We can try to fix it up or buy a new one.
why did Bob call his mother?
Hello, mom. It's Bob.
I'm so sorry.
What happened? I broke your glass doll yesterday.
I know it means a lot to you.
I'm afraid you may get angry.
So I hid it under my quilt.
It's okay. We can try to fix it up or buy a new one.
Question, why did Bob call his mother?
Four. right answer.
四听短文，根据短文内容选择正。
text twice. to this short summer course on fashion.
短文念两遍。
When I finish speaking, your teacher will take you to your classroom.
Thank you for being here at 8.30.
The early start was because there's so much information for you.
Classes begin at 9 o today.
And every two days, there's a change to the timetable.
On the one we sent you, says Wednesday is for the lesson on drawing, but it's
actually going on Tuesday.
Then on Thursday, the famous designer Peter Simons is coming to teach you.
We'll give you most of the things you need for the course, a pen, an iPad, and so
on. But please make sure you have your own smartphone to take photos.
You'll use it.
On the last day, you make something.
I'm sure you've made a skirt at least once already, so it will be a dress.
That's a little more difficult.
Hello, everyone. Welcome to this short summer course on fashion.
When I finish speaking, your teacher will take you to your classroom.
Thank you for being here at 8.30.
The early start was because there's so much information for you.
Classes begin at 9 o today.
We're going start.30.
So it will be a dress that's a little more difficult.
五听短文，根据短文内容完成图表中所缺信息。
短文念三遍。
has the right to a safe and happy life, but millions of people are still suffering
because of war.
The International Day of Peace on September 21st every year is a day when we try to
make a more peaceful world for everyone.
Peace means different things to different people.
To many, peace means no war.
Everyone can live without being scared or worried.
Peace also means being kind to other people.
Show your kindness and live with others in a peaceful way.
On this day, people keep silent for a minute.
It's also a good chance to let children take part in activities related to peace.
They draw pictures, write messages and poems about peace, or sing special songs.
You can also do a lot in the daily life.
You can try to bring peace to your own life by saying sorry and making peace with
someone you know, or you can try to help stop fights among your friends and
classmates. Standing up against bad behavior at school is also important.
Remember, small actions add up great things when they are done by millions of
people. Everyone has the right to a safe and happy life, but millions of people are
still suffering because of war.
The International Day of Peace on September 21st every year is a day when we try to
make a more peaceful world for everyone.
Peace means different things to different people.
To many, peace means no war.
Everyone can live without being scared or worried.
Peace also means being kind to other people.
Show your kindness and live with others in a peaceful way.
On this day, people keep silent for a minute.
It's also a good chance to let children take part in activities related to peace.
They draw pictures, write messages and poems about peace, or sing special songs.
You can also do a lot in the daily life.
You can try to bring peace to your own life by saying sorry and making peace with
someone you know, or you can try to help stop fights among your friends and
classmates. Standing up against bad behavior at school is also important.
Remember, actions add up great things when they are done by millions of people.
Everyone has the right to a safe and happy life, but millions of people are still
suffering because of war.
The International Day of Peace on September 21st every year is a day when we try to
make a more peaceful world for everyone.
Peace means different things to different people.
To many, peace means no war.
Everyone can live without being scared or worried.
Peace also means being kind to other people.
Show your kindness and live with others in a peaceful way.
On this day, people keep silent for a minute.
It's also a good chance to let children take part in activities related to peace.
They draw pictures, write messages and poems about peace, or sing special songs.
You can also do a lot in the daily life.
You can try to bring peace to your own life by saying sorry and making peace with
someone you know, or you can try to help stop fights among your friends and
classmates. Standing up against bad behavior at school is also important.
Remember, small actions add up great things when they are done by millions of
people.